,// creating an array and passing the number, questions, options, and answers
let questions = [
    {
    numb: 1,
    question: "What is the name of the safety sign as shown in the figure?",
    immg:"img1",
    answer: "Information Sign",
    options: [
      "Warn Sign",
      "Mandatory Sign",
      "Information Sign",
      "Danger Sign"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 2,
    question: "What is smothering in extinguishing of fire?",
    answer: "Isolating the fire from the supply of oxygen",
    options: [
      "Adding the fuel element to the fire",
      "Removing the fuel element from the fire",
      "Using of water to lower the temperature", 
      "Isolating the fire from the supply of oxygen"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 3,
    question: "Which step of the 5s-concept refers Standardization?",
    
    answer: "Step-4",
    options: [
      "Step-1",
      "Step-2",
      "Step-3",
      "Step-4"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 4,
    question: "Which pliers is used for making the wire hooks and loops?",
    answer: "Round nose pliers",
    options: [
      "Flat nose pliers",
      "Long nose pliers",
      "Round nose pliers",
      "Diagonal cutting pliers"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 5,
    question: "What is the use of the pincer?",
    answer: "Extracting the pin nails from the wood",
    options: [
      "Twisting the flexible wires",
      "Cutting larger diameter of wires",
      "Extracting the pin nails from the wood",
      "Holding small objects, where finger cannot reach"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 6,
    question: "Which plier is used for making wire hooks and loops?",
    answer: "Yellow",
    options: [
      "Blue",
      "White",
      "Yellow",
      "Green"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 7,
    question: "What is the use of pincer? ",
    answer: "Incineration",
    options: [
      "Landfill",
      "Composting",
      "Incineration",
      "Water compaction"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 8,
    question: "Which disposal method of waste save lot of energy?",
   
    answer: "Recycling",
    options: [
      "Land fill",
      "Recycling",
      "Incineration",
      "Composting"
    ]
  },
      {
    numb: 9,
    question: "What is the name of the tool as shown in the figure?",
    
    answer: "Diagonal cutting pliers",
    immg:"img9",
    options: [
      "Nose pliers",
      "Crimping tool",
      "Combination plier",
      "Diagonal cutting pliers"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 10,
    question: "What is the name of the file as shown in the figure?",
    immg:"img10",
    answer: "Halon type",
    options: [
      "Halon type",
      "Single cut file ",
      "Double cut file",
      "Curved cut file"
    ]
  },
     {
    numb: 11,
    question: "What is the name of the drill bit as shown in the figure?",
    immg:"img11",
    answer: "Taper shank bit",
    options: [
      "Flat drill bit",
      "Taper shank bit",
      "countersink bit",
      "straight shank bit"
    ]
  },
     {
    numb: 12,
    question: "Which file is used for sharpening the blunt teeth of a tenon saw?",
    
    answer: "Triangular file",
    options: [
      "square file",
      "round file",
      "Triangular file",
      "half round file"
    ]
  },
 {
    numb: 13,
    question: "What is the name of the part marked ‘X’ as shown in the figure?",
    immg:"img13",
    answer: "Heel",
    options: [
      "Edge",
      "Tang",
      "Heel",
      "point"
    ]
  },
{
    numb: 14,
    question: "What is the name of the hammer as shown in the figure?",
    
    answer: "claw hammer",
     immg:"img14",
    options: [
      "claw hammer",
      "Ball pein hammer",
      "Cross pein hammer",
      "Straight pein hammer"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 15,
    question: "What is the name of the tool as shown in the figure?",
     immg:"img15",
    answer: "Ball pein hammer",
    options: [
      "Claw hammer",
      "Tack hammer",
      "cross pein hammer",
     "Ball pein hammer"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 16,
    question: "Which is the physical hazard?",
    
    answer: "Vibration",
    options: [
      "smoking",
      "Vibration",
      "corrosive",
      "bacteria"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 17,
    question: "Which type of fire extinguisher is used for fire on electrical equipment?",
    
    answer: "Halon type",
    options: [
      "Halon type",
      "Foam type",
      "Gas cartridge water type",
      "Stored pressure water type"
    ]
  },
     {
    numb: 18,
    question: "What is the name of the tool as shown in the figure?",
      immg:"img18",
    answer:"pincer",
    options: [
      "wire stripper",
      "slide cutter",
      "pincer",
      "gimlet"
    ]
  },
       {
    numb: 19,
    question: "Which is the correct sequence of operation to be performed while using the fire extinguisher?",
    
    answer:"Pull, Aim, Squeeze, Sweep",
    options: [
      "Pull, Aim, Squeeze, Sweep",
      "Pull, Aim, Sweep, Squeeze",
      "Push, Arrange, Squeeze, Sweep",
      "Push, Arrange, Sweep, Sequence"
    ]
  },
        {
    numb: 20,
    question: "Which Personal Protective Equipment (PPE) is used for the protection from fumes?",
   
    answer:"Respirator",
    options: [
      "Apron",
      "Goggles",
      "Ear muff",
      "Respirator"
    ]
  },  
             {
    numb: 21,
    question: "What is starving in extinguishing of fire?",
    
    answer:"Removing fuel element from the fire",
    options: [
      "Adding fue to the fire",
      "Using water to cool the fire ",
      "Removing fuel element from the fire",
      "Preventing oxygen supply to the fire"
    ]
  },
                 
        {
    numb: 22,
    question: "Which artificial respiration method is to be performed to the victim with injuries on the chest and belly?",
    
    answer:"Mouth to mouth method",
    options: [
      "Schafers method",
      "Mouth to mouth method",
      "Holger Nelson back pressure method",
      "Nelson arm lift back pressure method"
    ]
  },  
     {
    numb: 23,
    question: "Which type of occupational health hazard is cause for infection due to bacteria?",
    
    answer:"Biological hazard",
    options: [
      "Electrical Hazard",
      "Physiological hazard",
      "Biological hazard",
      "Pschological hazard"
    ]
  }, 
     {
    numb: 24,
    question: "Which is the golden hour for the victim injured on head with risk of dying?",
    
    answer: "First 30 minutes",
    options: [
      "First 15 minutes",
      "First 30 minutes",
      "First 45 minutes",
     "First 60 minutes"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 25,
    question: " What immediate action should be taken to rescue the victim, if he is still in contact with the electrical power supply?",
    
    answer: "Break the contact by switching OFF the power supply",
    options: [
      "Pull or push him from the contact by hand",
      "Inform your authority about this electric shock",
      "Call someone for helping to remove him from contact",
     "Break the contact by switching OFF the power supply"
    ]
  },        
               {
    numb: 26,
    question: "What is the name of the cautionary sign?  ",
    immg:"img26",
    answer:"Pedestrian crossing",
    options: [
      "School",
      "Guarded",
      "Unguarded ",
      "Pedestrian crossing"
    ]
  }, 
     {
    numb: 27,
    question: " Which is the golden hour for the victim injured on head with risk of dying?",
    
    answer: "First 30 minutes",
    options: [
      "First 15 minutes",
      "First 30 minutes",
      "First 45 minutes",
     "First 60 minutes "
    ]
  },
          {
    numb: 28,
    question: "Which condition of the victim is referred as COMA stage? ",
    
    answer: "Lie totally senseless and do not respond to calls",
    options: [
      "Unconscious but can respond to calls",
      "Conscious but cannot respond to calls ",
      "Breathing but cannot respond to calls",
     "Lie totally senseless and do not respond to calls"
    ]
  },

      {
    numb: 29,
    question: "What is the cause for twisting defect in timber? ",
    
    answer: "Uneven shrinkage",
    options: [
      "Defective Storage",
      "Uneven shrinkage",
      "Improper seasoning",
     "Irregularity in growth of branches"
    ]
  },
      {
    numb: 30,
    question: "Which type of cold chisel is used for squaring materials at the corners?",
    
    answer: "Diamond point chisel",
    options: [
      "Web chisel",
      "Cross cut chisel",
      "Half round chisel",
     "Diamond point chisel"
    ]
  }
    
    
    
  // you can uncomment the below codes and make duplicate as more as you want to add question
  // but remember you need to give the numb value serialize like 1,2,3,5,6,7,8,9.....

  //   {
  //   numb: 6,
  //   question: "Your Question is Here",
  //   answer: "Correct answer of the question is here",
  //   options: [
  //     "Option 1",
  //     "option 2",
  //     "option 3",
  //     "option 4"
  //   ]
  // },
];
